hey everybody welcome to this a2 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and become a member at
patreon.com listeningtime to receive my
listening practice seminars extra
podcast episodes and sound training
videos ok today we're going to talk
about happiness this is a topic that we
all love and care about because everyone
wants to be happy first let's talk about
what happiness is some people think that
they need to find happiness other people
think that they can be happy all the
time
some people feel that happiness comes
from the things activities and people
that they love other people think that
happiness comes from within us
people have many different opinions
about happiness for me happiness is
influenced by internal and external
factors i think that we can choose to be
happy but the things around us can make
it easier or harder to make this choice
let's talk about some of the things that
might make us happy of course having
good relationships can make us happy if
you have good relationships with your
family members life is better however if
you have problems with your family or
fights with your family members this can
cause a lot of stress the same thing
applies to friendships if we have
friends who we can trust and who care
about us this gives us joy but on the
other hand if you don't have good
friends or if you have problems with
your friends this can make you unhappy
some people are more independent and
they don't need many friends but other
people are happier with many friends
another thing that sometimes makes
people happy is their work if you're
passionate about your job then working
can make you feel satisfied but many
people have jobs that they don't like
they dread going to work on monday
mornings and they're always looking
forward to the weekend
so these people might be unhappy on
weekdays and happy on weekends this
isn't the ideal situation it's important
to find a career that you enjoy
you don't have to love it but you
shouldn't be miserable either alright
another thing that makes people happy is
having hobbies when you find activities
that you like you can have a lot of fun
in your free time i always feel happier
when i dedicate sometime during the week
for my hobbies there are so many
different hobbies to choose from so i
think everyone can find one one more
thing that can make people happy is
traveling when you leave your comfort
zone and discover new things places and
people it helps you appreciate the world
i think most people experience positive
feelings when they go to new places
lastly let's talk about choosing to be
happy i mentioned that i think there are
things that make it easier to be happy
but we can choose to be happy even if
things aren't perfect if something
negative happens to you you don't need
to automatically feel unhappy you can
find the positive in the situation or
sometimes you can ignore it and move on
there are many negative frustrating and
inconvenient things in life however
these things don't always need to affect
our happiness it's not easy but i think
we can choose to be happy in many of
these situations ok that's all for today
remember to download the listening time
podcast and become a member at
patreon.comlisteningtime to receive my
listening practice seminars extra
podcast episodes and sound training
videos also subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram i'll see you next time
you